Makeshift
Well then, let's begin this meeting.
では、定例会議を始める
Given that there's only seven of them, one of the eight must have...
七人しかないところを見ると、八人の中の一人を…
I suppose they've most likely... killed him.
多分…やっちゃいましたね
In order to advance the Yotsuba Group's development further, whom should we kill?
我々ヨツバグループの更なる飛躍発展の為に…
誰を殺すか？
See! It's exactly like I said!
ほら、僕の言ったとおりでしょう？
This is bad... at this rate...
まずい…
このままいくと…
But before that, there are a few things we need to discuss.
その前に、今回はいくつか話し合うべき点がある
Firstly, we need to address Hatori's death.
まず、葉鳥が死んだこと…
It was unavoidable.
仕方ないだろ
Besides, if I'm honest, I'm kind of relieved that Hatori is dead.
正直、葉鳥が死んでくれて、私はホッとした
Kira has clearly shown us what will happen to those who try to leave this group.
この会議から抜けようとする者がどうなるか…
キラははっきりと見せしめにしたんだ
…うん
I believe everyone here has understood the significance of Hatori's death.
いいな、これで葉鳥の死の意味は十分わかったと思う
Let this be a lesson to us all.
肝に銘じろ
Next, Erald Coil's report...
次、エラルド．コイルの報告書の方だが…
仲間の死の事だっというのに、たったこれだけ…
One of their members has died, and that's all they've got to say?!
So, this report is what our $5 million paid for?
500万ドルの代償がこの報告書か…
He hasn't uncovered any vital information, such as L's face or name.
L の顔や名前、肝心なところが何にもわかってないじゃないか
Is this guy, Coil, really going to be of any use?
本当に役に立つのか？このコイルって奴
Wait.
まあ待て、コイルはこの報告書の最後で、
At the end of the report he warns us not to underestimate L's existence.
L の存在は軽視すべきものではないとの忠告をくれたりもしている
"Given your current pace... particularly the fact that the deaths which benefit the Yotsuba Group occur every Friday and Saturday...
このペース…特に「金曜．土曜に
ヨツバにとって有利に働く死が毎週では、
L がキラと関連づける可能性がある」と…
it's possible that L will connect this to Kira."
To be able to figure this much out about us, Coil's a pretty capable guy in my book.
私たちのやってる事を
そこまで調べあげたコイルは…やはり有能だと思う
At any rate, we need to reconsider our current plan of killing off people towards the end of each week.
とりあえず毎週末に殺人というのは改善しべきだ
T-This is incredible. The confessions just seem to keep on coming.
す…凄いですね
がんがん自白してるって感じだ
ああ…もうこの録画があれば、七人を逮捕できるんじゃないか？
Surely, with this recording, we'd be able to arrest all seven of them?
Just as I thought, this is bad...
やはりまずい…
Kira's not being very versatile with this, huh?
キラは融通利かないよな
They should at least attempt to spread them out over the course of the week.
一週間適当に割り振ってくれればいいのに
I think that since Coil's realized this, it's going to be too risky to carry on killing at our current pace.
私は、コイルが気づいた以上
今のペースで殺していくのは危険だと考える
From now on, we've got to be more discreet, and ensure that no one else finds out about this.
ここからはさらに慎重に、
絶対に誰にもバレないようにしていくべきだ
From now on, we've got to be more discreet, and ensure that no one else finds out about this.
うん…
Alright then, moving on to the main issue; whom should we kill?
では、本題に入る
誰を殺すか？
The launch of E.L.F. Insurance in Japan... if we don't stop that,
ELF 保険の日本進出…これは喰い止めないと
then the Yotsuba Group, among other companies, will lose a lot of clients.
他社含め、ヨツバの顧客も多くが流れる
Agreed.
賛成だ
So, with regards to E.L.F., shall we go with accidental deaths for those on this list?
では、ELF はここに挙がっている者を…事故死でいいな？
No objections.
異議なし
What on earth?! Just like that?!
何だこれは…
こんな簡単に…
Another target is the one who's opposing the Yotsuba Group's plans for a resort.
もう一人は…
ヨツバのリゾート計画に反対している、釘沢組の前西三太郎氏
Another target is the one who's opposing the Yotsuba Group's plans for a resort.
Mr. Zenzai Santorou of the Kugisawa Group.
Zenzai suffers from high blood pressure, so we can specify a date for him to suffer a stroke. How's that?
前西はかなり高血圧で悩んでるので、
「時間指定の脳卒中」等の病死で可
Zenzai suffers from high blood pressure, so we can specify a date for him to suffer a stroke. How's that?
これでいいか？
No objections.
異議なし
Kira, accidental death, death through illness, specifying exact times...
キラ、事故死、病死、死の時間設定…
It's exactly like we thought! There's no mistake about it!
僕達の考えていた通りだ、もう間違いない
No, unfortunately, until said people actually die, we can't say that for sure.
いいえ、残念ですが
今挙げられた者が死んで初めて「間違いない」です
From what these seven have disclosed at this meeting,
この七人の会議での言動
as long as we closely monitor the actions of those seven until those mentioned at the meeting die...
そして会議で挙げられた者が死ぬまでの…七人の行動
if we always closely monitor these things from now on... without a doubt, we'll catch Kira.
これをこれからずっと事細かに観ていけば…
必ずキラを捕まえられます
Ryuuzaki!!
竜崎！
What's up with both of you?
…なんですか？二人揃って…
I can't go along with your plan! It's wrong!
竜崎の考えているやり方はできない…間違っている！
I knew it...
ほら来た…
It's apparent that your plan is to allow those seven to continue killing in order to catch Kira, but I can't do that!
この七人に殺しを続けさせていく事で
キラを捕まえようとしているようだが…そんな事はできない
It's apparent that your plan is to allow those seven to continue killing in order to catch Kira, but I can't do that!
He's right! The seven of them are clearly murdering people!
そうだ
明らかにこの七人は殺しをしている
松田の証言と、この影像を出すところに出せば
Surely we can prove this with Matsuda's testimony and these video tapes?!
立証できるのでは？
It's quite a dilemma... if we do arrest them now, everything we've worked for will be ruined.
困りましたね
今捕まえてしまったら、全てが台無しになります
It's quite a dilemma... if we do arrest them now, everything we've worked for will be ruined.
So, we'll request Kira to kill the E.L.F. people in three weeks' time, and Zenzai this weekend.
じゃあ、ELF は、三週間後
前西は今週末にキラに頼むということで、どうだ？
How's that?
異議なし
No objections.
This weekend?! There's no time left!
今週末ということになれば、もう時間がない
Light, do you have the phone numbers for all seven?
月、あの七人の携帯番号は、もうわかっていたな？
Yes.
ああ
It doesn't matter who, we need to contact one of them and force them to call off the murders.
とにかく、誰でもいい
七人の誰かに電話して、殺人をやめさせる…
待ってください
Wait a minute please. If we do that, it'll mean that they've been discovered just three days after Aiber got in contact with them.
そんなことをしたら、
アイバーが彼らに接触した三日後に
捜査の手が伸びた事になり、怪しまれます
It'll look suspicious.
Most importantly, it's extremely likely that doing so would make it impossible for us to figure out who Kira is.
それと何よりも、
キラが誰なのか断定できなくなる可能性が極めて高い
Most importantly, it's extremely likely that doing so would make it impossible for us to figure out who Kira is.
After all this work, we'd be back at square one.
せっかくここまで来て、また振り出しになります
In order to catch Kira, we need to be able to prove that they are Kira.
キラを捕まえる為には、キラだという証拠がどうしても…
Ryuuzaki, if Kira really is one of those seven, is it fair to assume that if we call one of them,
竜崎、仮にこの七人の中にキラがいたとして…
この中の一人に電話をし、
そいつにあたる可能性は七分の一と、考えていいのか？
the chance of them being Kira is one in seven?
え？
I was thinking that there'd be two at most, so I'd say two out of seven.
私は多くても二人…
七分の二と考えてますが…
If we're already prepared for them to find out that they're being investigated,
どうせ捜査の手が伸びていると知られる覚悟なら、
then it's worth betting on the two out of seven.
その七分の二に賭けてみよう
I'm going to borrow the title "L", Ryuuzaki.
L の名を借りるぞ、竜崎
Someone who, from the conversation, looks unlikely to be Kira, yet is still influential... that would be...
今までの会話でキラではなさそうで
それなりの発言力を持っていそうなのは…
Ooi!
Namikawa!
奈南川
尾々井
If you're going to call, use the phones in this building.
電話するならここのを使ってください
They can't be traced or tapped.
逆探も盗聴もできないようになっています
Ideally we would just wipe out all the executives of our rival enterprises, one after the other.
本当は、ライバル企業の幹部を片っ端から
ぶっ殺していくのは手っ取り早いが
That would be the fastest method, but I guess it doesn't work like that...
いくらなんでもそれはな
殺して株分けちまおう
Is this the Director of the First Trade Department, Namikawa Reiji-san?
ヨツバグループ第一営業部部長、奈南川零司さんですね
Yes? That's right.
ああ、そうだが？
Please give out natural responses while listening to me.
適当に相槌を打って聞いてください
I am L.
私は L です
Cameras and bugging equipment have been set up in that meeting room.
その会議室には、カメラと盗聴器が仕掛けてあり
The entire meeting has been recorded by us.
今の会議の影像は全て撮りました
You began the talks with Hatori's death, and then went on to discuss who you should kill.
冒頭の話題は葉鳥氏の死の事、会議の内容は誰を殺すか…
Am I right?
そうですね？
He's seen everything!
完全に見られている…
If you're not Kira or negotiating directly with them, I can make a deal with you.
もしあなたがキラ、
もしくはキラと直接交渉できる人間でないのなら
If you're not Kira or negotiating directly with them, I can make a deal with you.
取引しましょう
A deal?!
取引…!?
Postpone the murders of the E.L.F. president, and Zenzai by a month.
ELF 長と、前西氏を殺すのを、一ヶ月先に延ばしてください
I doubt that will prove too difficult for you.
あなたなら、難しい事ではないと思います
I see...
死を不規則にするから
うむ、そうか…
カレンダーにダーツすればいいのさ
うん、それで？
And then?
If you do this and cooperate with us from now on, you will...
それをして頂いて、今後私たちに協力してもらえれば
あなたの罪…あっいえ
no, in fact, all except Kira will be considered as attending these meetings under duress, and will not be charged.
キラ以外の者は、
キラに脅されその会議に参加していたとして、罪は問わない
Oh, really...
ああ、そうか…
Now I've got no choice but to side with L.
これでは L につくしか…
No, if Kira finds out that I've sided with L, they'll kill me... what should I do?
いや… L についたとキラにわかったら殺される…
どうすれば…
If you tell people about this phone call, it'll just cause a panic.
この電話の内容をバラせば、パニックになる
It'll do you no favors, and you'll all be caught.
あなたにプラスはない
皆捕まえることになります
However, my aim is to go head-to-head with Kira.
しかし、私の目的はキラとの一騎討ちです
Listen carefully... if L beats Kira, you won't be charged; if Kira beats L, you get to continue your affluent life.
いいですか…
L がキラに勝てば、あなたは無罪
Listen carefully... if L beats Kira, you won't be charged; if Kira beats L, you get to continue your affluent life.
キラが L に勝てば、あなた方はそのまま裕福な人生
You should just play along with both sides and see what happens.
あなたはどちらにも合わせておき、傍観していればいい
L 、キラ、どちらが勝っても、あなたに損はない
L or Kira, whoever wins, you can't lose.
The only way for you to lose... is if you're caught right now.
あなたにとっての損は、今、捕まってしまう事です
He's already figured out what my final decision has got to be.
私が最終的に出すであろうを答えを先に見抜いている…
Well then?
では…
ああ、月曜日に
Fine, on Monday.
What is it, Namikawa? Who was it?
どうした奈南川、誰からだ
One of my men has messed up. I'll have to deal with it on Monday.
いや、部下がまたヘマをして月曜に尻拭いだ…
Sorry for the interruption. Let's get back on topic.
中断させてすまない
話を戻そう
As for when we're going to kill the E.L.F. members and Zenzai...
ELF の奴等と前西をいつ殺すかだが…
How about we give Coil a month, and if he still hasn't discovered L's identity by then, we'll kill them off on random dates.
こういうのはどうだ？
一ヶ月コイルに時間を与え
How about we give Coil a month, and if he still hasn't discovered L's identity by then, we'll kill them off on random dates.
一ヶ月経てまだ L の正体がわからなければ
やむをえん、日をばらつかせて殺す
Then, we'll give him another month, and repeat.
次も一ヶ月与え…という繰り返しで
Once L is out of the way, we can resume killing two or three each fortnight.
L を始末できたら隔週で２．３人ペースに戻す
Basically, our main priority should be to deal with L.
つまり、 L を始末するのを優先するということだ
I see. It's true that if we deal with L, we'll have no one left in our way.
なるほど…
確かに L を殺せば、もう邪魔はなくなる
Until then, we should tread carefully.
それまでは慎重にか…
うん…それでいいんじゃないか？
That might work.
Well, it can't hurt to play it safe.
ま、石橋を叩くくらいじゃないとな
In that case, we'll give Coil a month.
では、コイルに一ヶ月与えることにする
異議なし
No objections!
L should be satisfied with this...
L …
この場はこれで満足だろう…
However, we'll continue to meet on a fortnightly basis.
しかし、会議は隔週で行う、以上
Meeting closed.
It seems to have worked.
うまくいきましたね
Yeah...
ああ
Yagami-kun, you really are amazing.
やっぱり夜神君は凄いです
Not only did you manage to postpone the killings, but we might even be able to obtain information from Namikawa.
殺しを延期させるだけではなく、
奈南川から情報を得られるかもしれません
Not only did you manage to postpone the killings, but we might even be able to obtain information from Namikawa.
Your methods are similar to mine, and you managed to think of this before I did.
しかも私のやり方に似ていますし、私より早く考えついた
In that case...
これなら…
If I die, you may be able to carry on the name of "L".
もし私が死んでも、
夜神君が L の名を継いでいけるかもしれません
If I die, you may be able to carry on the name of "L".
What are you talking about?!
何を縁起でもない事を…
We have a month to deduce who Kira is, and to find the proof.
これで、一ヶ月以内にキラを断定し、
証拠まで挙げなくてはならなくなった
The challenge begins now.
ここからが勝負だろ
Yes...
はい…
However, since you were the first to notice the Yotsuba Group, it's fair to say that you may be more capable than I.
しかしヨツバに最初に目をつけたのも夜神君ですし
やはり、私より有能と言っていいかも…
It's possible that you may be able to handle it, Yagami-kun.
夜神君ならできるかもしれません
If I were to die...
もし私が死んだら…
...would you succeed me as L?
L を継いでもらえますか？
If I were to die, would you succeed me... with the name of "L"?
私が死んだら、継いでもらえますか？
L の名を…
If he's Kira, and is putting on an act, he'll definitely answer "yes".
キラで演技をしているのなら、必ず「継ぐ」と答えるはず
What are you talking about, Ryuuzaki?
何言ってるんだ竜崎
As long as we're wearing these, we'll die together--
これをしている限り、死ぬ時は一緒じゃないのか…
Oh, I get it...
そうか…
Ryuuzaki, I'm sorry, but I'm going to have to speak your thoughts aloud to everyone else here.
竜崎
悪いが、今竜崎が考えている事を、皆の前で言わせてもらう
Ryuuzaki is thinking that if I were Kira, then either I still am Kira right now and just pretending otherwise,
竜崎は、僕がキラなら
今、僕がキラである事をしらばっくれ
演技でこうしているか…
or Kira's power have passed to someone else, and right now I have no recollection of being Kira.
ちから
キラの能力が他の者に渡り、
今の僕にはキラだった自覚がなくなっている…という
Those are the two patterns.
ふたつのパターンを考えている
If it is the former, and I am just acting, then he can never take these handcuffs off.
前者…僕が演技をしているのなら
この手錠は絶対に外せない
No, even if I wasn't acting, he probably wouldn't remove the handcuffs.
あっいや、
演技じゃない方のパターンでも、手錠は外せないだろう…
No, even if I wasn't acting, he probably wouldn't remove the handcuffs.
He's thinking that I was Kira, and even though that power may have passed to someone else,
竜崎は僕がキラだったと考えているし、
もしその能力が人に渡ったのだとしても…
I might have set things up so that the power will return to me.
ちから
もう一度その能力が
僕に戻ってくるように仕組んであると考えている
Basically, it's not that I was simply being manipulated,
つまり、単に操られていたのではなく
rather, I may have transferred the power to someone, and have planned to regain it once the suspicions against me had been lifted.
自分から人に渡し、
自分の疑いが晴れたところで能力を戻すという策略…
Amazing... he knew exactly what I was thinking...
凄い…
私の考えている事をここまで的確に…
Amazing... he knew exactly what I was thinking...
Ryuuzaki was thinking that, "after L's position is his, Yagami Light will become Kira".
竜崎は、「夜神月が L の座を奪った上でのキラになる」
そう考えた
Correct.
正解です
L と同等の地位を得て
To gain the same status as L and be in a position to even manipulate the police... while secretly being Kira.
警察なども自由に動かせる立場にあり、裏ではキラ
I would be invincible.
最強だな…
And you think that I'm capable of achieving this... no, in fact you are saying I would do this.
それを僕にならできる…
いや、やりかねない…
そういう意味で言ったんだな
Yes.
はい
But what do you think now?
しかしどうだ
If nothing else, you must have realized that I'm not acting, right?
これで少なくとも、僕が演技している
わけではないというのは、わかったんじゃないか
You mean that if you were putting on an act to take my position you wouldn't be revealing your plan to everyone, am I right?
演技をし、 L の座を奪うことを狙っているのなら
その計画を皆の前でばらすはずがない…
You mean that if you were putting on an act to take my position you wouldn't be revealing your plan to everyone, am I right?
ということですね？
Ryuuzaki...
竜崎
この僕が…今存在するキラを捕まえたそのあとで……
Do you truly believe that after catching the current Kira, I'd go on to become Kira... A murderer?
キラに…殺人犯になると思うか？
Do you really see me as that kind of human being?!
そんな人間に見えるのか？
I believe so.
思います
I can see it in you.
見えます
A-Again...
ま…また……
Okay! An eye for an eye!
はい、一回は一回
Let's just call this a draw and be done with it!
今回は相討ちという事で、これでおしまい
Yeah, that's right. For now, we've got to catch the Kira that's right in front of us.
…そうだな
とにかく今は、目の前にいるキラを捕まえることだ
As long as we're wearing these handcuffs, you can't have any complaints.
手錠をしてさえいれば、文句ないはずだ
そうですね
You're right, we've only got a month left.
もう一ヶ月しか時間がないんですし
竜崎
Ryuuzaki?
はい
Yes?
If we can use the footage of that meeting as evidence to arrest those seven, won't the judging of criminals stop as well?
さっきの会議を証拠に、あの七人を捕まえることができれば
犯罪者の裁きも止むのでは？
Again...
また……
Unfortunately...
残念でした
…っ、残念？
"Unfortunately"?
あの七人の中にキラがいるとは限りません
...we can't be certain that Kira is among those seven.
繋がりを持っているだけであれば、
あの七人がキラに殺されるだけです
If Kira is only connected to them, and we arrest them, then all that will happen is that those seven will be killed.
Unless we know for sure that one of those seven is Kira, there's no point in arresting them...
七人の中に絶対キラがいる
というのでなけらば、今捕まえる意味はありませんし
and even if Kira is among them, it's difficult to say who it is right now.
仮にいたとしても、現在誰がキラなのか判定は難しい
It's still too early to tell.
まだ時期尚早だと私は思います
B-But if we can't say that Kira is definitely not among those seven,
し…しかし
七人の中に絶対いないとも言えないなら
七人を捕まえれば、殺人が止まる可能性もあるはずだ
there's a possibility that if we arrest them, the murders will cease.
It's as my father says. There is that possibility.
確かに父さんの言うとおりだ、その可能性はある
あの…
Umm, I think I'll chase Kira on my own after all.
やっぱり私は、一人でキラを追います
この本部は夜神さん達にもお貸ししますし、私も使う
I'll let you use these headquarters and I'll continue to use them myself as well.
夜神さん達は夜神さん達のやり方で、
捕まえるなり好きなようにしてください
Yagami-san and the rest of you can continue to pursue Kira as you wish, using your own methods.
私は私のやり方で捜査していきます
I'll investigate using my own methods.
そうしないと口論になるだけです
Unless we do this, it'll just end in arguments.
Let's just go our separate ways.
別行動にしましょう
In other words, you insist on narrowing it down before you pursue Kira?
つまり…竜崎はあくまでも、キラに絞って追うということか
Yes.
はい
We can't solve this case unless Kira is caught.
この事件はキラを捕まえなければ解決しない
目の前の何人かの死を阻止する事が、
意味のない事だとは言いません
I'm not saying that there's no point in stopping the deaths of the criminals in front of you,
but unless we expose all truths to the light, Kira will appear again, and consequently, the victims will increase in numbers.
しかし全ての真相を解明しなければ
またキラは現れ、犠牲者は結果的に増える
That being the case, it's my belief that we need to confirm Kira's identity through those seven.
ならば…
何人よりもキラを断定すべきというのが、私の考えです
That being the case, it's my belief that we need to confirm Kira's identity through those seven.
I'm against the arrest of those seven, so if you're planning to do it, it's your responsibility.
私は七人逮捕には反対ですから
やるなら夜神さん達の責任でお願いします
I'm against the arrest of those seven, so if you're planning to do it, it's your responsibility.
私は私でキラを追う
I'll pursure Kira by myself.
We have a month. It'll depend on which of us is fastest.
期限は一ヶ月
どっちが早いかですね
り…竜崎
Ryuuzaki! Where are you going?
どこ行くんだ？
弥の部屋です
To Amane's room.
すみません、月君もお父さん側だとわかっていますが
I'm sorry. Light-kun, I know you're on your father's side, but I'll need you to come with me as I can't remove the handcuffs.
手錠は外せないので付き合ってもらいます
Light! Is it okay if we go on a date today?
ライト、今日デートOK の日だっけ？…
Even if Ryuuzaki-san has got to come...
竜崎さん付きの
海砂さん
Misa-san?
Do you love Light-kun?
あなた月君を愛していますか？
えっ…？
Y-Yes... very much.
あっ…はい、とっても…
And yet, you also admire Kira?
しかしキラも崇拝している
Yes...
…はい
では、月君とキラだったらどっちを取りますか？
So, if you had to choose between them, who would you pick?
Huh?! Light, of course!
はあ？
そんなのライトに決まってるじゃん
キラには感謝して会いたいと
思ってたこともあるけど、愛なんかじゃないし
It's true that I'm grateful to Kira and I've wanted to meet them in the past, but that isn't love!
It'll definitely have to be Light.
断然ライトです
And Light-kun, you want to catch Kira. Don't you, Light-kun?
月君はキラを捕まえたい
そうですね？月君
Yes, of course.
ああ、決まってるだろ
He wants to catch them. Now, what do you think of that?
捕まえたいそうです、さあ…どうします？
If Light wants to catch them, then I want them caught too.
ライトが捕まえたいたら、捕まって欲しいと思います
So, if it was possible, you would want to be of use to Light-kun, and help him investigate, correct?
では月君の役に立ち、
月君と一緒に捜査できるなら協力したい…ですね
R-Ryuuzaki!
竜…竜崎
うん、ライトの為になるなら、ミサは何でもします
Yeah! Misa would do anything for Light!
-_-
Just wait a minute! What are you planning?!
ち…ちょっと待て
何をする気だ
We'll get Erald Coil to report to those seven that he's got a lead that suggests that Amane Misa may know L in some way.
「エラルド．コイルから、
弥海砂が L を知っているかもしれないという線が出た」と
あの七人に報告させます
And that "Amane Misa was interrogated on suspicion of being the second Kira".
弥海砂は第二のキラの容疑で L に取調べを受けたらしいと…
That's true too.
それマジだしね
If they think that there's a chance that Amane Misa knows L,
弥海砂が L の事を知っているかもしれないとなれば…
必ずヨツバは海砂さんをCM に起用し、
色々聞き出そうとしてきます
they'll definitely employ her to be in their commercials, and attempt to question her.
That time Matsuda messed up, he did ask for her to be hired for a commercial, after all.
もう松田さんのドジの時…
CM などで使ってくれとは話をしてありますし
うんうん
Yup, yup!
No way.
それは駄目だ
Why?
なんで？
海砂が危険な目に遭うからに決まってるだろ
Because that would put you in danger, of course.
You're worried about my safety? Yay!
え…私の身を案じてくれるの？
やった
But Misa would do anything for you. This is nothing.
でも海砂、ライトの為なら、それくらいなんでもないよ
Listen Misa, if they think you know L, they'll try any means possible to get you to admit it.
いいか海砂
L の事を知っているかもしれないとなれば
Listen Misa, if they think you know L, they'll try any means possible to get you to admit it.
相手はどんな手でそれを言わせようとしてくるかわからない
It'll be fine! No matter how much they torture Misa, she won't say a thing!
大丈夫、海砂どんな拷問されたって言わないもん
はい、そうですね
Yeah, that's right.
We know that Kira can manipulate people before their deaths.
大体キラは、死の直前の行動を操れる
There's a real chance that they'll manipulate Misa into talking before killing her.
海砂を操って、喋らせて殺すという恐れが十分ある
In fact, if they kill L, they'll no longer have a use for her, and will kill her in order to silence her.
いや…
L を殺せば用がなくなり、口封じにキラは海砂をきっと殺す…
In fact, if they kill L, they'll no longer have a use for her, and will kill her in order to silence her.
I wouldn't want that...
それはさすがに嫌だ
Light-kun...
月君
我々が勝てば海砂さんは死にません、それに…
as long as we win, Misa-san won't die.
Also, as long as we're connected by these handcuffs, we'll share the same destiny.
手錠がある以上、運命を共にするんですよね
If I die, you'll die too.
私が死んだら月君も死ぬ…
And if that happens, the saddest person will be Misa-san.
そうしたら一番悲しむのは海砂さんじゃないですか
私や月君が死ぬか、キラが捕まるかです
Either Light-kun and I die, or we catch Kira.
So, which is it?
さあ、どっち？
Catch Kira! I can't live in a world without Light!
キラ捕まる！
ライトのいない世界じゃ、私生きていけない
That's correct!
はい、正解
Hey, Ryuuzaki! You're going too far!
…おい、竜崎、無茶苦茶だ
We don't have time. I'm in a hurry here.
時間がないんです、私焦ってます
Besides, Amane Misa's willpower and love for Light-kun are beyond comparison in this world.
それに弥海砂
この子の根性と…月君への愛は
世界一です
R-Ryuuzaki-san...
竜…竜崎さん…
Misa may have been misjudging you until now!
海砂今まで、あなたのこと誤解してたかもしれない
Calling you a pervert and so on...
変態とか言っちゃって…
ちゃんと私を理解してくれるのね…
But in reality, you actually understand me!
Yeah, Misa-san is an excellent lady, completely worthy of Light-kun.
はい～海砂さんは月君にふさわしい最高の女性です
はあ？
やぁ
Thanks, Ryuuzaki!
ありがとう、竜崎
…好きになりますよ
I might fall for you...
いえ…それはちょっと…
Erm, I'm not so keen on that... how about we say "we're friends", Ryuuzaki-san?
お友達ということでどうでしょう、竜崎さん
Yes.
はい
I've made another friend.
また友達が増えました
Yup! All of Light's friends are Misa's friends too!
うん、ライトの友達はみ～んな海砂の友達
Let's all get along!
仲良くやりましょう
わ～い、わ～い
And Misa never sells out her friends!
そして海砂は、友達を絶対裏切れません
三人力を合わせて、キラ逮捕
The three of us will combine our powers and catch that Kira!
Well actually, Yagami-kun wants to approach the investigation with his father in a different way than I.
いえ、それが…
夜神君は私と違う捜査方法をお父さん達と取るようで
Well actually, Yagami-kun wants to approach the investigation with his father in a different way than I.
私と海砂さん、二人ということで…
So, it'll just be the two of us: Misa-san and myself.
Huh?! What's up with that?!
え～なにそれ
You play pretty dirty, Ryuuzaki... you're giving me no choice but to join this investiga--
やり方が汚いぞ竜崎…
これじゃ僕は、こっちの捜査に加わるしか…
No. We're fine.
いえ、結構ですよ
何言ってんの、ライトも参加決定
What are you talking about?!
Light's joining too! It's decided!
No, that's not it! I'm against the methods used in this investigation itself. It's too dangerous for Misa.
いや、違う
この捜査自体に、僕は反対なんだ
No, that's not it! I'm against the methods used in this investigation itself. It's too dangerous for Misa.
海砂が危険すぎる
Light... thank you so much for thinking of me.
ライト…私のこと思ってくれてありがとう
でもやらせて
But let me do this. Misa wants to be useful to you, Light.
海砂、ライトの役に立ちたい
役に立って、ライトにもっと愛されたい…
I want to be able to help you, so that you'll love me even more.
Besides, Misa will quite happily die for you.
それに海砂は、ライトの為なら、喜んで死ねる…
As I thought, given the current situation, it'll prove difficult to arrest those seven.
やはり現状では七人の逮捕は難しいか…
Any good ideas, Mogi? Matsuda?
何か、いい策はないか？模木…松田
To be continued
まあ、海砂演技派だしね
西中監督、ライト達…
今度は死神さんにまで演技しろって言われちゃって
ちょっと大変
大きなCM も入ってきてそうだし
売れっ子だね！